const quizShapes = [
    {
        question: "Q1 : A  solid object has 6 faces, 12 edges and 8 corners. This object could be a...?",
        a: "Cylinder",
        b: "Cuboid",
        c: "Cone",
        d: "Sphere",
        ans: "ans2" 
    },
    {
        question: "Q2 : How many faces does a Cube have?",
        a: "6",
        b: "8",
        c: "4",
        d: "12",
        ans: "ans1" 
    },
    {
        question: "Q3 : A perfectly round solid is called a...?",
        a: "Cylinder",
        b: "Cuboid",
        c: "Cone",
        d: "Sphere",
        ans: "ans4" 
    },
    {
        question: "Q4 : How many flat faces does a Cylinder have? ",
        a: "2",
        b: "0",
        c: "3",
        d: "6",
        ans: "ans1" 
    },
    {
        question: "Q5 : How many edges does a cube have? ",
        a: "8",
        b: "4",
        c: "6",
        d: "12",
        ans: "ans2" 
    },
    {
        question: "Q6 : What 3D shape looks like a book?",
        a: "Cylinder",
        b: "Cuboid",
        c: "Cone",
        d: "Sphere",
        ans: "ans2" 
    },
    {
        question: "Q7 : How many faces does a Sphere have?",
        a: "0",
        b: "2",
        c: "1",
        d: "4",
        ans: "ans3" 
    },
    {
        question: "Q8 : What 3D shape looks like a ball?",
        a: "Cylinder",
        b: "Cuboid",
        c: "Cone",
        d: "Sphere",
        ans: "ans4" 
    },
    {
        question: "Q9 : Which 3D shape has all equal edges?",
        a: "Cylinder",
        b: "Cube",
        c: "Cone",
        d: "Sphere",
        ans: "ans2" 
    },
    {
        question: "Q10 : How many vertices does a Cone have?",
        a: "0",
        b: "1",
        c: "2",
        d: "3",
        ans: "ans2" 
    }
];

const question = document.querySelector('.question');
const option1 = document.querySelector('#option1');
const option2 = document.querySelector('#option2');
const option3 = document.querySelector('#option3');
const option4 = document.querySelector('#option4');
const submit = document.querySelector('#submit');

const answers = document.querySelectorAll('.answer');

const showScore = document.querySelector('#showScore');

let questionCount = 0;
let score = 0;

const loadQuestion = ( ) => {
    const questionList = quizShapes[questionCount];

    question.innerText = questionList.question;

    option1.innerText = questionList.a;
    option2.innerText = questionList.b;
    option3.innerText = questionList.c;
    option4.innerText = questionList.d;
}

loadQuestion();

const getCheckAnswer = () => {
    let answer;

    answers.forEach((curAnsElem) => {
        if(curAnsElem.checked){
            answer = curAnsElem.id;
        }
    });

    return answer;
};

const deselectAll = () => {
    answers.forEach((curAnsElem) => curAnsElem.checked = false );
}

submit.addEventListener('click', () => {
    const checkedAnswer = getCheckAnswer();
    console.log(checkedAnswer);

    if(checkedAnswer === quizShapes[questionCount].ans){
        score++;
    };

    questionCount++;

    deselectAll();

    if(questionCount < quizShapes.length){
        loadQuestion();
    }else{

        showScore.innerHTML = `
        <h3> You scored ${score}/${quizShapes.length} ✌️</h3>
        <button class="btn" onclick="location.reload()">Play Again!</button>

        `;

        showScore.classList.remove('scoreArea');
    }
});